Liberation News Service Photographs
Special Collections Research Center
Liberation News Service Photographs
1976 1980
1976-1980
SCRC 482
Special Collections Research Center
0.25 Linear Feet
1 box
Liberation News Service (New York, N.Y.)
Cockrell, Cathy, 1951-
Content Description
Photographs and negatives taken by Cathy Cockrell, who worked for the Liberation News Service from 1975 to 1978, for Liberation News Service stories. Photographs document working conditions, protests, Gay Pride celebrations, and other places and subjects primarily in New York City, with some photographs taken in Philadelphia, Washington, DC, and other cities.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Related Materials
Liberation News Services Records, SCRC 173, Special Collections Research Center, Temple University Libraries, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
Liberation News Service Photographs, 1965-1981, bulk 1970-1979, Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive, New York University.
Youth Liberation Press Records, SCRC 175, Special Collections Research Center, Temple University Libraries, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
Custodial History
Donated by Cathy Cockrell, August 31, 2020.
News agencies--United States; Press and politics--United States--History--20th century; Radicalism--United States--History--20th century; Underground press publications--United States--History--20th century; New York (N.Y.); Photographs; Negatives; Philadelphia (Pa.); Gay pride celebrations; Washington (D.C.); Liberation News Service (New York, N.Y.)
- Demonstration against Philippine dictator Ferdinand Marcos; Demonstration supporting Chile, Washington, DC (frames 6-9 at bottom), negatives (negative sleeve # 701), 1976 1978; circa 1976-1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lesbian rights demonstration, New York City, negatives (negative sleeve # 711), 1976 1978; circa 1976-1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 2)
- LGBT rights demonstration; possibly a different LGBT demonstration in frames 50-60; Activist Doris (Blue) Lunden (wearing necklaces); Doris Lunden and Marjorie Ackerman in frame 60, negatives and prints (negative sleeve # 715), 1976 1978; circa 1976-1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lower East Side scenes (E 4th St.) used in LNS packets, negatives and prints (negative sleeve # 104), 1976 1978; circa 1976-1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Nursing home workers strike, Lower East Side, New York City, negatives (negative sleeve # 113), 1976 1978; circa 1976-1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Electronics factory, Philadelphia, negatives and prints (negative sleeve # 300), 1976; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Electronics factory, Philadelphia, negatives and prints (negative sleeve # 301), 1976; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 7)
- People's Bicentennial rally, Philadelphia, negatives and prints (negative sleeve # 307), July 4, 1976; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Liberation News Service move to 17 W. 17th St, New York City; Frame 5: Judy Rabinovitz in frame 5; Milton Tam & Sarah Plant with printing press in frame 42; negatives (negative sleeve # 613), 1976-06 1976-08; Summer 1976; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Suit and garment factory, Philadelphia, negatives and prints (negative sleeve # 302), October 1976; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Suit and garment factory, Philadelphia; Italian market, Philadelphia; Demonstration supporting political prisoner Susan Saxe, Philadelphia, negatves and prints (negative sleeve # 303), October 1976; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Gay Pride demonstration; Latin social club, Lower East Side, New York City, negatives (negative sleeve # 201), 1977?; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Gay Pride, New York City, negatives (negative slide # 712), June 1977; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Upper West Side street scenes, New York City; Street fair (turtle race); Gay Pride demonstration, negatives (negative sleeve #200), 1977-06 1977-08; Summer 1977; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Pro choice speak-out held at Washington Irving High School, New York City, negatives (negative sleeves # 702A and 702B), September 10, 1977; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 15)
- United Mine Workers of America (UMWA) strike, Blue Diamond Coal Company's Justus Mine in Stearns, Kentucky, and Union hall in Whitley City, negatives and prints. See LNS coverage, packets # 891, 896, 897 (negatives sleeves # 720-722), November 28, 1977; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 16)
- LGBT demonstration, 1977, including protest against Anita Bryant's "Save Our Children" campaign, New York City; Gay Pride 1978, New York City (frames 10-19A), negatives (negative sleeve # 713), 1977 1978; 1977-1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Puerto Rican activists Julio, Luis and Andres Rosado and Chicano activist Pedro Archuleta in a New York City Jail, negatives. See LNS coverage, packet #901 (negative sleeve # 700A), February 17, 1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Gay rights demonstration, New York City (frame 18, 19 includes LNS collective member Joan Gibbs), negatives (negative sleeve # 710), April 16, 1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Puerto Rican activists Julio, Luis and Andres Rosado and Chicano activist Pedro Archuleta being released from a New York City Jail, negatives. See LNS coverage, packet #901 (negative sleeve # 700B), May 8, 1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Puerto Rican activists Julio, Luis and Andres Rosado and Chicano activist Pedro Archuleta being released from a New York City Jail, negatives and prints. See LNS coverage, packet #901 (negative sleeve # 701A and 701B), May 8, 1979; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Gay Pride 1978, New York City, negatives (negative sleeve # 714), June 25, 1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 22)
- National Equal Rights Amendment march, Washington, D.C., negatives and prints (negative sleeve # 265), July 9, 1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Demonstration outside Bedford Hills Correctional Facility for Women, Bedford Hills, New York, negatives and prints (negative sleeve # 260), August 27, 1978; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Anti-nuclear demonstration, Washington, DC, with LNS staffer Joan Gibbs, negatives (negative sleeve # 206), 1979; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Dykes Opposed to Nuclear Technology (D.O.N.T.) demonstration at Indian Point nuclear reactor (frame 41Apossibly a different event), negatives (negative sleeve #202), May 1979; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Women Against Pornography march, Times Square, New York City; Public transit strike, New York City, negatives (negative sleeve # 210), October 20, 1979; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Public transit strike, New York City, women on E. 4th Street (Ave. C/D), negatives and prints (negative sleeve # 211), April 1980; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Anti-nuclear demonstration, Hartford, Connecticut, negatives (negative sleeve # 204), May 6, 1980; 1 Folders (Box 1, Folder 29)